Onondaga Community College Student Publications Collection
Onondaga Community College
Onondaga Community College Student Publications Collection
1963 - 2018
The Onondaga Community College Student Publications Collection contains printed newspapers, newsletters, journals, magazines and yearbooks and related files published by students from the early years of the college to the present time.
13 linear feet
Onondaga Community College
This collection is open to researchers without restriction.
This collection is open to researchers without restriction.
Student publications began at Onondaga Community College shortly after the opening of the college in 1962. The "OCC Press" was the first student run newspaper, publishing its first newspaper in 1962. Several bi-weekly and monthly publications followed, including "The Blue Banner", "Fred Magazine", "The Other Paper", and a variety of literary magazines. The longest running newspaper was "The Overview", published between 1975 - 2015. Today students continue to publish newsletters, magazines and journals.
Onondaga Community College; newspapers; periodicals; College student newspapers and periodicals; black-and-white photographs; memorandums; school yearbooks; correspondence; School yearbooks
The Onondaga Community College Student Publications contains publications from the founding of the college in 1962 to the present day. Publications include newspapers, newsletters, the college yearbook, journals and magazines. The topics range from news of the campus, politics, social issues, and works of fiction. This collection is updated continuously with the latest issues of the students publications. Each series is organized into narrower sub-series and then arranged chronologically.
Series 1 - Student Newspapers - Student newspapers were published from the early years of the college and continued through the years. The 2 largest and longest running student newspapers were "The Blue Banner" and "The Overview". Others were published, and collected by the archives. Date coverage 1963-1990.
Series 2 - Student Magazines and Journals - Student literary, political, artistic and campus centered journals were published through the years. Date coverage 1989-2018.
Series 3 - Student Yearbook - The Yearbooks for Onondaga Community College began with the Plaza Program in 1963. In 1964 the yearbook was titled the Chieftain, and continued until 1975. This was the last yearbook published. Date coverage 1963-1975. These yearbooks were digitized and can be found on the New York Heritage website: https://nyheritage.org
- Student Newspapers, 1963 - 1990
  - "Blue Banner" Newspaper, 1963 - 1972 (Box PUB1)
    - "Blue Banner" Correspondence, 1963 - 1972 (Box-folder PUB3-2)
    - "Blue Banner" Constitution, 1963 (Box-folder PUB3-1)
    - "Blue Banner" Newspaper, 1963 - 1972 (Box PUB1)
    - "Blue Banner" Photographs, 1963-1972 (Box-folder PUB3-12)
  - "The Bridge", 2000 - 2001 (Box PUB4)
    - "The Bridge: the Voice of the Student Government", 2000 - 2001 (Box-folder PUB4-1)
  - "Campus Clipboard", 1971 - 1976 (Box PUB4)
    - "Campus Clipboard": Memos, 1973 (Box-folder PUB4-1A)
    - "Campus Clipboard", 1971 - 1976 (Box-folder PUB4-7)
  - "Candlelight Review", 1971 (Box PUB4)
    - "Candlelight Review", May, 1971 (Box-folder PUB4-8)
  - "This Week at OCC", 1970 - 1972 (Box PUB4)
    - "This Week at OCC", 1970 - 1972 (Box-folder PUB4-9)
  - "The Other Paper", 1972 - 1973 (Box PUB2A)
    - "The Other Paper" Memos, 1972 (Box-folder PUB10A-3)
    - "The Other Paper" Newspapers, 1972 - 1973 (Box PUB2A)
  - "OCC Press", 1962 - 1963 (Box PUB6)
    - "OCC Press" Newspaper, 1962 - 1963 (Box-folder PUB-2,3)
  - "The Overview", 1975 - 1990
    - "The Overview" - Memos, 1975 - 1978 (Box-folder PUB10A-2)
    - "The Overview" - Charter, 1975 (Box-folder PUB10A-1)
    - "The Overview" Newspaper, 1975 - 2015 (Box PUB10-PUB23)
- Student Magazines/Journals, 1989 - 2018
  - "Fred Magazine", March, 1989 (Box-folder PUB6-1)
  - "Graffiti Magazine", 1970 - 1974 (Box PUB25)
    - "Graffiti Magazine" - Constitution, 1967 (Box-folder PUB25-1)
    - "Graffiti Magazine" - Memos, 1967 (Box-folder PUB25- 2)
    - "Graffiti Magazine" - Photographs, 1970 - 1971 (Box-folder PUB25-3)
    - "Graffiti Magazine", 1968 - 1974 (Box PUB25)
  - "Fallacy, Fantasy and the Art of Flying on Wisps of Words", undated (Box-folder PUB25-4)
  - "Whirlpool", 1975 (Box PUB25)
  - "Shapes and Chimeras", 1975 (Box PUB25)
  - "Etchings on the Hour Glass", 1980 (Box PUB25)
  - "The Oracle: Literary Magazine of Onondaga Community College", 1985 - 1997 (Box PUB2A)
  - "Textuality", 2007 - 2009 (Box-folder PUB28-1)
  - "Parnassus: Onondaga Community College Literary Magazine", 2005 - 2006 (Box-folder PUB28-2)
  - "The Lazer", 2010 (Box-folder PUB28-3)
  - "Writers on the Rock", 2012 - 2018 (Box PUB26)
- Student Yearbook, 1963 - 1975
  - Yearbook - Memos, 1963 - 1971 (Box-folder PUB4-4)
  - Yearbook, 1961 - 1973